UNITE Northeast Department Photographs 6000/012 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE Northeast Department Photographs
1962-1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE)
6000/012 P
3.17 cubic feet
3.2 linear ft.
Photographs.
7673084
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 03, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Biographical / Historical
UNITE, the Union of Needle Trades, Industrial, and Textile Employees was formed in 1995 after a merger between the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU).
In 2004 they announced they would merge with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) which created UNITE HERE.
Jay Mazur served as president of UNITE from its beginning until his retirement in 2001. Bruce Raynor was elected president at that time and served until the HERE merger.
Scope and Contents
This is a collection of over 1,500 photographs documenting UNITE's Northeast Dept.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6000/012: UNITE Northeast Department Files 6000/012 AV: UNITE Northeast Department Audio-Visual Materials 6000/016 MB: UNITE Local 169 Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Memorabilia Banners 6000/016 P: UNITE Local 169 Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Photographs 6000/021: UNITE Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Research Files
Textile industry -- New York (State); Textile workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Clothing trade -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union --Photographs; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Photographs; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees --Photographs; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees. Northeast Department--Photographs; UNITE HERE (Organization) --Photographs
7673084
- Holiday parties (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  29 photographs
- Individual member photographs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  17 photographs
- Local 295 parade photographs (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Leslie Fay Strike photographs (Box 1, Folder 4)
  23 photographs
- Militant Action Team - strike photographs (Box 1, Folder 5)
  41 photographs
- Strike photographs (Box 1, Folder 6)
  5 photographs
- Dorothy Neg's Retirement (Box 1, Folder 7)
  16 photographs
- 100th Anniversary Dunmore parade Participation (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 9)
  20 photographs
- Miscellaneous Shop Shots, LUF Training Awards (Box 1, Folder 10)
  28 photographs
- Young Demos Outing, Summer 1962, Ros Grove, Carbondale Demo Steak Fry, Popis Grove - 9/30/1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  27 photographs
- Severance - Lau Rose - September 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  10 photographs
- Convention, Atlantic City, July 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Conbar-Casey Shop visits Institute Carbondale (Box 1, Folder 14)
  14 photographs
- Richardson Dilworth's visit to Mary DeFazio's Home (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Allentown Fair, Reading Convention - Label (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cook out Dushore Lingerie - Aug. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  9 photographs
- Cornell Dedication - 10/2/1962; Institute-Croton - 8/1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Bowl-er-ama-Ceder Lanes - 8/26/1962; General bowling (Box 1, Folder 19)
  57 photographs
- NLV Shot Coverage (Box 1, Folder 20)
  21 photographs
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 21)
  2 photographs
- Rolls Royce (Box 1, Folder 22)
  3 photographs
- One day trip to Unity House Summer 1962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  6 photographs
- Local 385 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  35 photographs
- Lynn Yeakel Fall 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  19 photographs
- Pittston Xmas Party - 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  25 photographs
- Unity -- 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  15 photographs
- Water damage - Pittston Bldg (Box 2, Folder 5)
  48 photographs
- Chancy D'Elia Strike (Box 2, Folder 6)
- LF Ratification - July 13, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  26 photographs
- Picket Lines - 4/4/1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Prayer meeting - July 14, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  1 photograph
- Senator Wofford on Picket Line - 6/4/1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Wall Street - 6/25/1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Leslie Faye Ratification - May 28, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Bowling Party (Box 2, Folder 14)
  18 photographs
- Camp Solidarity -- 10/1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Elect Wofford - 4/24/1994 - Cookout (Box 2, Folder 16)
  12 photographs
- Parades (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Unidentified Woman (Box 2, Folder 18)
  4 photographs
- Leon's Retirement - 9/1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Walter Mondale (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Mondale (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Individual photos of unidentified women (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Unity House - Rank and File - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 2, Folder 24)
  137 photographs
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 2, Folder 25)
  13 photographs
- Party photographs (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Leslie Fay Photographs (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Ted Kennedy photographs (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Peerless Workers at Kaufman's (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Labor Day 1983 - Scranton (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Negatives (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Political Campaign Rafalkos Pepper Rally - Oct 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Ame's Shower Curtain Co., Inc. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  77 photographs
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 3, Folder 9)
  175 photographs
- Mike (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Jean Konelski from Mary Goldolems (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Lois Miller (Box 3, Folder 12)
  11 photographs
- Lois Hartel - 12/15/1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Negatives (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Holiday Party (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 3/1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Film interviewer of Louise (Hbg) 1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Mondale -- 1984 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Family -- 8/1984 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  7 photographs
- 12/1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- District Council -- 10/4 Extras (Box 3, Folder 25)
- People Helping People (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Ferraro and members - 9/1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  8 photographs
- Misc. photographs (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Walsh (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Retirees Cook Out May-Aug - Park, Aug 1983 -- Trip to Lewistown PAOP and Wilkes-Barre Utility (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Social events - fashion shows; Anniv. party (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Clambake 1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Scranton District Council (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Strike - Oct. 1982 - Vamilla (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Scranton District Council - X-mas decoration class (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Seamsters ILS (return to Aggy) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Misc. photos (Box 4, Folder 12)
- July Bond Strike (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Negatives - Spring Summer 1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Chairladies Weekend 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- PUC hearing on people - 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Rank and File Seminar Unity - Summer 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Misc. Photos (Box 4, Folder 18)
  44 photographs
- Misc. Photos (Box 4, Folder 19)
  1 photographs
- Misc. photos and slides (Box 4, Folder 20)
  4 photographs; 5 slides
- WRC Annual Meeting 11/28/1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Misc. ILGWU photos (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Negatives (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Convention photos (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Cooperation Achievement Productivity (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Negatives (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 5, Folder 2)
  92 photographs
- Local 365 - Imports protest (Box 5, Folder 3)
- NEPAC, Chapter 30 UNITE! (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Carpenters Local 514, Wilkes Barre, PA (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Parade; Local 15253 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Greater Birmingham Habitat for Humanity (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Convention photographs (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Kingston Fosh (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Lois Hartel photographs (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Assorted Photographs (Box 5, Folder 11)
  108 photographs
- Miscellaneous photographs in need of preservation (Box 5, Folder 12)
  8 photographs - rolled, ripped and brittle
- 25th Convention of ILGWU; Delegates in Session at 25th Convention ILGWU, Boston, Mass, May 31st, 1944; Opening Session, 25th Convention ILGWU, Boston, mass, May 29th, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  2 photographs; oversize, rolled and wrinkled. Photos could be put into a photo preservation project